# Alfredo J. Calzadilla

Address: 5750 NW 42<sup>nd</sup> Court, Boca Raton, FL 33496. Email: alfredojcalzadilla@gmail.com

Telephone: 425-524-9794 Nationality: U.S. Citizen.

#### **CAREER PROFILE**

FP&A Manager offering 7+ years of strong progressive finance experience. Proficient at processing and analyzing data from multiple sources, modeling complex financial business cases, analyzing financial results and projections, and advising corporations, small businesses and investors on investment opportunities and strategies to maximize profitability.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FP&A Manager

April 2018 – May 2020

Impar Capital

Madrid – Spain

Industry: Real Estate Investment and Development

- Designed and implemented new FP&A systems, models policies and procedures to increase work processes efficiencies within the Finance Department and improve accuracy of financial analyses and reports.
- Built complex financial pro forma models in Microsoft Excel to perform financial feasibility analyses on potential acquisitions of commercial, residential and lodging real estate assets.
- Underwrote the acquisition of seven new real estate investment assets, which raised approx. 37M Euros of equity.
- Designed complex macros in Microsoft VBA to automatically perform financial sensitivity analyses.
- Designed equity waterfall models in Microsoft Excel with 5+ IRR hurdles to forecast variable cash distributions.
- Advised senior management, investors and clients on new investment opportunities and investment strategies.
- Reported to investors monthly and quarterly detailed financial results, projections and variance analyses.
- Built real estate investment portfolios by consolidating the financial statements of different investment projects.
- Trained, led and managed the FP&A team on maintaining the new financial models that I had built, updating them with actuals and forecasts, and on generating periodic and ad-hoc financial reports for Sr. Managers and investors.

# **Senior Financial Analyst**

March 2016 – April 2018 Kent, WA – United States

Thyssenkrupp Aerospace North America

Industry: Aerospace Manufacturing

- Partnered with plant managers and department heads to build annual budgets and estimate cash projections.
- Generated the quarterly and annual financial reporting statements (Balance Sheet, P&L and Statement of Cash Flows) of multiple manufacturing facilities and discussed the financial results with the CFO and senior managers.
- Developed an interactive and automated financial model in Microsoft Excel used to forecast and consolidate the balance sheets, P&L and cash flow statements of multiple manufacturing facilities.
- Compiled and analyzed operational and financial data from different sources to produce financial insights, analyze business cases and submit recommendations to Senior Managers.
- Built complex regression analyses to assess the correlation between operational variables and financial results.
- Developed complex financial models to assess the risk, profitability and feasibility of new capex projects.
- Submitted thorough business cases and recommendations on the acquisition of new capex projects to the CFO.
- Analyzed different pricing scenarios for new bid proposals by building financial models in Microsoft Excel.
- Prepared presentations, business cases and financial analyses for the CFO and directors in Germany.

**Financial Analyst** 

Kolter Homes

April 2014 - February 2016

Industry: Land Development and Home Building

Palm Beach Gardens, FL – United States

- Designed, built and maintained complex discounted cash flow models and used them to calculate Key Financial Performance Indicators to evaluate the profitability and financial performance of real estate investment projects.
- Led the annual budgeting and bi-annual financial planning processes of 12+ Real Estate development projects.
- Analyzed sales projections and market trends to propose changes in pricing, and evaluated their impact on KPIs.
- Developed a pricing analysis tool through the design of an automated model in Microsoft Excel with VBA macros.

- Built financing models to assess the impact of new construction and development loans on the profitability and financial performance of the projects.
- Periodically updated cash flow models with actuals, optimized complex formulas to forecast different streams of cash flow, and generated actuals vs. forecast variance analysis reports.
- Reported the financial results, projections and variances of projects to senior managers, investors and the CEO.

### **Contract Administrator / Financial Analyst**

April 2013 - March 2014

Caracas - Venezuela

Grupo PMA, S.A.

Industry: Construction and Project Management

- Estimated and forecasted construction costs for materials and labor.
- Prepared annual construction budgets.
- Built cash flow models in MS Excel to assess the profitability of residential and commercial construction projects.
- Coordinated the procurement and sale of construction equipment, construction materials and services.
- Analyzed bid proposals for construction materials, equipment and services, and awarded contracts to suppliers.
- Monitored the construction work progress and contractor performance while ensuring contract requirements.

**Credit Analyst** 

February 2012 – April 2013

JPMorgan Chase

Jacksonville, FL - United States

Industry: Banking, Home-Lending

- Completed Chase's Credit Training Program to review, approve and decline residential mortgage applications.
- Underwrote residential mortgage applications from the company's high net-worth clients with a value of up to \$1.5M.
- Analyzed borrower's credit, income, asset and appraisal documentation to determine the creditworthiness of the applicant, and either approve, counter offer or decline their mortgage application.
- Provided recommendations to loan officers and loan processors on loan alternatives and investor guidelines.
- Ranked in top 10% of analysts in the site and company, as of 2012 year-end review for strong performance.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **IBM Data Science Professional Certificate**

IBM Developer Skills Network

Issued: January 2021

Online program

# MSc. in Business Management

University of Florida (UF) - GPA: 3.88 out of 4.00

Graduated: December 2011
Gainesville. FL – United States

# **BSc.** in Civil Engineering

Universidad Metropolitana - GPA: 3.68 out of 5.00

Graduated: October 2009 Caracas – Venezuela

## **LANGUAGES & SKILLS**

# Languages:

- English: Fluent Level C2. Pearson Test of English (PTE): 87 out of 90 possible points.
- Spanish: Native proficiency.

### **Programming Skills:**

- VBA: Develop programs to perform advanced spreadsheet automations and to optimize complex financial tools and models.
- Python: Develop scripts for data processing and analysis, data visualization and machine learning models.
- SQL: Write intermediate level queries for pulling, processing and transforming data.

# **Computer Skills:**

- Advanced proficiency in Microsoft Office, especially in Microsoft Excel.
- Basic proficiency in SAP and Microsoft Access.